FELIPE SANZ

(+34) 663 567 994 | felipesanze@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Recent experience with Data Science and Machine Learning methods. Dual national having lived in 5 different countries and trilingual in English, French and Spanish. Experience in large European financial institutions as part of investment decision-making team. Avid drummer, singer, and self-taught ukulele player.

EDUCATION

IE SCHOOL OF HUMAN SCIENCES AND TECHNOLOGY

MADRID, SPAIN

Master's in Business Analytics and Big Data (MBD)

Apr. 2021 - Mar. 2022

• Key subjects: Machine learning (I, II & III), SQL, NoSQL, Spark, Data visualization and storytelling, Big data architectures, Recommendation engines, Social network analysis, NLP.

University of St Gallen (HSG)

ST GALLEN, SWITZERLAND

Bachelor of Science in Management (Exchange year)

SEP. 2018 – Jun. 2019

Key subjects: Quantitative finance, Time series analysis, Financial institutions, Monetary policy, Financial analysis.

HEC LAUSANNE LAUSANNE, SWITZERLAND

Bachelor of Science in Management (BSc Management)

SEP. 2015 - JUN. 2019

• Key subjects: Econometrics, Financial Mathematics, Risk Management, Accounting, Micro/Macroeconomics.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

HELLO CHANGE MADRID, SPAIN

START UP - Product Development & Data Intern

MAY. 2021 - PRESENT

Design of a pioneering personality test measuring an individual's comfort with uncertainty

- Developed test score prediction model using multiple Machine Learning algorithms, as part of a 3-person team
 <u>Result</u>: Enhanced score prediction quality, making the test more reliable from a product perspective
- Carried out quantitative and qualitative market research for development of a secondary product
 Result: Company designed 2 educational programs aiming to improve students' comfort with uncertainty

LYRIQUE PRIVATE EQUITY

GENEVA AREA, SWITZERLAND

Private Equity Intern (Investment Management)

Mar. 2020 - Dec. 2020

- Managed a pipeline of prospect funds by establishing 1st contact with fund managers in capital raising stage
- Added value in all stages of the Fund Due Diligence process (fund strategy, track record, market and risks)
 Result: Company achieved over €30M of capital commitments in into 4 PE funds with expected IRR of 21% /yr
- Performed a thorough mapping of the PE Secondaries market and made subsequent recommendations as a
 healthy alternative for investors during COVID-19 crisis. Included quantitative data analysis and interviews
 Result: Company built a €50M proprietary Fund of Funds focusing on 10 selected PE secondary funds

DEUTSCHE BANK

LUXEMBOURG, LUXEMBOURG

Wealth Management Intern (Investment Management)

Jun. 2019 - Dec. 2019

- Operated the Standard Lombard business and supported credit officers through the Structured Lending process
- Backed Front Office with management of Key European Client accounts

OTHER EXPERIENCE

THE MOVEMENT (STARTUP)

MADRID, SPAIN

Co-founder (Fitness)

APR. 2021 - PRESENT

• Reached finals of IE Business School Venture Lab contest (in progress)

LE SHOP DU MOBILIER ('THE FURNITURE SHOP', SOCIAL ENTREPRENEURSHIP)

LAUSANNE, SWITZERLAND

Co-founder, Assistant Manager (Retail)

SEP. 2017 - JUN. 2018

Won 3rd place prize of university-wide startup contest and accomplished all project objectives

LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGY

- English (fluent) | French (fluent) | Spanish (native) | German (intermediate)
- SQL | Python (for data science) | R | Git | NoSQL (MongoDB) | Py Spark